James Carter

(816) 551-7254
Email
Linkedin Profile
Portfolio
GitHub

SUMMARY

A full stack web developer with training and experience in the full software development lifecycle. Proven skills in planning, development, and software quality assurance. A highly motivated developer with strong front & back-end development skills. A self-starter, attentive to details, resourceful in finding the right solutions. Soft skills include patience, perseverance, teamwork, and analytical. Experience working in Agile Scrum environment and project management. Ability to visualize high level project concept and materialize UI flow, produce implementation plan, and documentation for team members.

COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages

Microsoft Technology Associate Certified: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python

Proficient in: C#, ASP.NET

Familiar with: Angular 2+

Software

• Database: Microsoft SQL Server, MongoDB, Firebase

Software Testing: Jira, Silk Test

EXPERIENCE

QA Analyst (USDA FSA)

2018-2018 (Contract)

Ace Information Services

- Served as quality assurance member of a cross-functional Agile Scrum development team that
 consisted of the project's managers, developers, and quality assurance.
- Verified website completeness regarding functional/business requirements
- Created manual test cases for websites that included 10-60 test cases per page.
- Identified technical bugs/errors and ensured the website is error-free
- Responsible for updating testing results in JIRA

Typesetter 2010-2014

Allen Press

- Corrected fonts, styles, justification, paragraph, line, word and letter spacing errors in scientific
 journals
- Verified illustrations and pictures met specified criteria for printing
- Ensured good presentation and readability

EDUCATION

Centriq 2016-2017

Leawood, KS

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development